JYOTI PRAKASH MOHANTA

WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACT

+91 - 8658963394

jyotiprakashmohanta32@gmail.com

Jamjarki, Nodhana, Mayurbhanj Odisha, 757081

SKILLS

HTML / CSS / JAVASCRIPT

Node Js / Express is

React Js / Next Js

Core Java / Hibernate / Spring Boot

Docker / Jenkins / AWS Instance

MySql / Mongodb

EDUCATION

B. Tech

C .V Raman Global University

2018-2022

CGPA - 8.10

+2 / Class 12

Seemanta Mahavidyalaya

2014 - 2016

Percentage - 70 %

SOCIAL

GitHub

https://github.com/jyotiprakash-m

linkedin

https://www.linkedin.com/in/jyotiprakash-m/

PROFILE

Jyoti Prakash Mohanta has 6 months of professional experience and 10 months of internship experience. He is serving notice period. He has good understanding of java backend , node js backend ,react js, next js , HTML ,CSS , JavaScript and other tools like docker, Jenkins .He also have experience in integrating the block chain smart contract in react and next js framework . He is very self motivated and passionate about learning new technology

WORK EXPERIENCE

Junior Associate Technology

Publicis Sapient

May 2022 - Present

- Build one microservice from scratch . Create one Jenkins pipeline for CI / CD
- · Build frontend using Reactis.
- Deploy the backend application in AWS.
- Use Prometheus and Grafana for monitoring the microservice. Write test cases for each APIs with coverage 80%.

Frontend Developer Intern

BAChain

February 2022 - April 202

- Main responsibility was to support and development of different web pages using the React Js framework as well as specific libraries such as web3.s in order to interact with remote polygon nodes.
- Develop front web application using React.js, HTML, CSS as well as blockchain libraries.

Frontend Developer Intern

iTalent India

July 2021 - October 2021

Work on the live project of the company and build the frontend of 4 features
i'e - Issues management system, Issue management in Calendar view,
Meeting management system.

React Developer Intern

SleekSites.in

March 2021 - June 2021

 Build a e-learning platform having features like Dashboard Page, All course display page, Purchase Page, Notes review Page and Test Page.

PROJECTS

1. Pet Clinic Backend Code Frontend Code

 Has different different service like vet Service, Owner Service, Visit Service, Eureka Server and api-gateway. Frontend is build with react is.

2. Map Pinner Code

• One user can create his profile and pin any location in the map.

3. MERN Blog Code

• This is basic blog application with node js backend and react js frontend

4. Space - X Mission Finder Code Live

 This website give all information of recent mission done by space - x and having advance searching features.